Okay, so in this video we are going to
briefly discuss the ITTOs of resource
management, rather input tools and
techniques of resource management.
And again, we're just going to briefly
discuss them because, again, just want to
reiterate ITTOs are not a huge major
portion of the exam.
You don't need to memorize them,
first of all, because it's too many.
And then secondly, you know, because,
you will not be getting tons of questions
on what's the input of this and what's the
output of that.
you just need to have a basic decent
understanding.
Now, there are six processes in resource
management, right?
So we'll just briefly, quickly cover some
of the major ITTOs.
So remember, the very
first process in planning is
always going to be plan
something management, right?
In this case, something meaning in
knowledge area.
So in this case, we're talking resources,
so plan resource management, and then the
output is going to be that management
planning.
case the resource management plan and
again any of these management plans and
the first process a plan we're documenting
or we're planning how right how are we
going to estimate our resources how we're
going to get our resource how we're going
to acquire them how we're going to monitor
and control them how we're going to be
managing our resources all documenting
procedures right also remember you've got
physical resources and team
resources physical resources
refers to anything but
humans, basically, right?
Equipment supplies, raw
materials, facilities, whereas
team resources or human
resources refers to team members.
And so from the team side of it,
the human resource side of it,
they have another
output of the team charter,
which again, we have a separate video for.
Also, now, one of the other
tools and techniques we'll be
covering is something called
the RACI chart, the RAC chart.
That's one of the key tools and
techniques.
this falls under a responsibility
assignment matrix.
Now, what's one of the starting points?
In order to plan what resources we need,
well, we might refer to the project
charter, might refer to other plans as
well.
So that's why we have project management
plan and other project documents as well,
as an input.
Now, one of the other processes is
estimate activity resources, right?
So activity, so basically what
it's saying is for each activity,
what equipment supplies,
labor, raw materials are needed.
So we're trying to determine
the physical resources
and the team resources
to actually do the work.
And so resource requirement then is one of
the outputs, right, one of the key
artifacts, if you like, for each activity,
what equipment supplies, labor,
raw materials are required.
You may create a resource breakdown
structure, similar to a work breakdown
structure, but in this case, a resource
breakdown structure.
right, which is basically showing then,
again, for this project, you know,
what different resources, what equipment
is required, what supplies are required,
what team members are required,
grade and quality of raw materials and
skill sets for team members, that's all a
consideration to make.
You'll see some of these tools and
techniques, right, we've covered in other
knowledge areas, tools and techniques,
and in fact, these inputs and outputs as
well, they're all shared amongst many,
many different processes.
So we have, we've covered these in
separate processes here.
Right, some of the considerations to make,
an input for estimating your resources,
right?
Well, we need to know our activity.
What activity are we looking at is
estimate activity resources.
So the activity list is
going to be one of the key
inputs, as well as availability
of resources and cost.
They're all going to play a major
consideration in determining, you know,
what resources we need, when we need them,
and so and so forth.
Now, once we've estimated
what resources we need, we
figured out, all right, we
need this machine, right?
We need this skill set for team members.
Then now we need to go out and acquire
them.
We need to physically get those resources,
right?
So this refers to securing the
team and physical resources
actually needed to do the
work, actually securing them.
Right, so the output here in this case,
of the artifact we're creating,
physical resource assignment, project team
assignment.
And really all that means is things like
you're adding a name to a role.
This person has been assigned this role on
your project.
That's really what this is referring to.
Or we have secured our building.
We've secured this building that we need
for this project.
We've secured this machine.
We've ordered raw materials.
Now, some of these resources could be
internal to your project
or could be external.
right.
And so negotiation, right, you're going to
be negotiating for these resources.
It's going to be negotiating these
machines.
You're going to be
negotiating functional managers
to release team members
to work on your team.
That's a simple example.
And then plus, you might be negotiating
contracts as well for raw materials,
equipment, external vendors, consultants,
contractors, and so and so forth.
Resource calendar is documenting the
availability of resources.
Right.
So, So that would be one of the artifacts
there as well.
Also then, develop team, right?
Developed team specifically then refers to
your team, obviously, right?
It refers to team resources.
And, you know, we're
going to discuss this,
that your project is only
as good as your team.
So a team, developed team refers to the
interaction of team members.
Right, you want your team members to get
to know one another.
So team performance assessment then is
going to be one of the, key outputs here.
How well is the team performing?
And then some of these
tools and techniques, again,
we're going to be, we're going
to be documenting as well.
We're going to be some of these tools and
techniques.
We're going to be covering in other videos
as well.
Co-location virtual teams, right,
is a major consideration.
Right.
So you're going to, our team is going to
interact differently based on whether
they're co-located
face-to-face in an office
environment or they're working virtually.
Right.
Now, in this day and age, you know,
with the whole COVID situation,
then, co-location is not as common,
right, as it was before, right?
But there's different procedures for team
members to get to know one another and
interact with one another based on whether
they're co-located or working remotely,
right?
Communication is a huge, important aspect.
And communication
technology, right, especially
when team members are working virtually.
So that's going to be one of the tools and
techniques you're going to be utilizing.
Right.
Plus interpersonal skills, right,
it's going to be a key part, right,
because it's up to you
as a project manager
to engage and motivate your team, right?
So that's going to be one of the key tools
and techniques.
And then this also refers to then,
leadership, right, emotional intelligence.
And these are all new
items that PMI have added
to the syllabus, which
is not part of PIMBO.
It's not part of the ITTOs, right,
but it is part of the new syllabus.
2021 exam content outline syllabus.
Now, then you've got managed team,
right?
Managed team refers to individual team
member.
How well are individual team members
performing?
And one of the other key tools here then,
change request here
refers to staffing changes.
You need to move team members from one
team to another team.
That's really what that is referring to.
And then again, key part of this,
key part of managing teams and team
members is your interpersonal and team
skills, right, emotional intelligence,
leadership.
Again, there's a whole bunch
of new items on the syllabus,
which we're going to be
covering in in separate videos.
And then monitoring controlling, right,
actually controlling the resources, right?
Just basically tracking the plan versus
the actual.
Now, monitoring
controlling, right, control
resources refers to
physical resources, right?
And again, we have workforce as
information as the output that we see over.
over and over again, writing
monitoring and controlling
because you're comparing
your actual results with your plan.
Actual results is work performance data.
You're comparing it with your plan to get
your information.
And information, remember, is the
interpretation.
The data comes from executing.
You're comparing it with your plan to get
your work performance information.